Alchemy is a science where one understands the structure of matter, breaks it down, then rebuilds it.
錬金術は物質を理解分解再構築する科学なり
However, it is not an all-powerful technique,
as one cannot create something out of nothing.
されど　万能の技にはあらず
無から有を生ずることあたわず
If one wishes to gain something,
one must present something of equal value.
何かを得ようと欲すれば
必ず同等の代価を支払うものなり
This is the concept of equivalent exchange, the fundamental basis of alchemy.
これすなわち錬金術の基本　等価交換なり
However, there is a taboo in alchemy. Human transmutation.
錬金術師に禁忌あり
そは人体錬成なり
One must not commit this act.
これ何人も犯すことなかれ
I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
この想いを　消してしまうには
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
I want to go back and finish
やり残してるコト
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
やり直してみたいから
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
夢のつづき　追いかけていたはずなのに
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
曲がりくねった　細い道　人につまずく
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
あの頃みたいにって　戻りたい訳じゃないの
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
無くしてきた空を　探してる
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
わかってくれますように
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
犠牲になったような　悲しい顔はやめてよ
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
罪の最後は涙じゃないよ
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
ずっと苦しく背負ってくんだ
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
出口見えない感情迷路に
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
誰を待ってるの？
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
白いノートに綴ったように
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
もっと素直に吐き出したいよ
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
何から　逃れたいんだ
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
…現実ってやつ？
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
叶えるために　生きてるんだって
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
叫びたくなるよ　聞こえていますか？
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
無難になんて　やってられないから
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
…帰る場所も無いの
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
優しさには　いつも感謝してる
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
だから強くなりたい(I'm on the the
(I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
懐かしくなる
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
こんな痛みも歓迎じゃん
Konna itami mo kangei jan
兄さん
Brother.
Hm?
リオールの教主の噂　どう思う
What do you think about the rumors of the High Priest of Lior?
奇跡の業なぁ
Miracles, huh?
何もない空間から花を錬成するってんだろ
He creates flowers out of nothingness, right?
単なる手品かもしれないが
It could just be a sleight of hand, but...
もし　そうでなければ
But if it isn't...
Yeah... It could be what we've been looking for.
ああ　ひょっとするとひょっとするかもしれないな
クセルクセスを一夜で滅ぼした天上の石
A heavenly stone that destroyed Xerxes overnight.
東の賢者によって封印された大エリクシル
The great elixir that had been sealed away by a sage from the west.
呼び名はいろいろあるけど
There are many names for it, but to put it simply, it is something that reinforces alchemy.
つまりは　錬金術を強化してくれるもの
それが賢者の石
That is the Philosopher's Stone.
これがあれば　アルの体を取り戻せるかもしれないのに
If we had this, we could get your body back...
くっそ　もっと詳しく書いとけよ
Dammit! Why is this all that's written down?!
アル
Al.
Yeah?
何
今度こそ　当たりだといいな
Wouldn't it be great if it's the real stone this time?
Yeah. Definitely.
うん そうだね
10 Years Ago   Resembool
エド アル
Ed, Al, where are you?
どこ
あらま
Oh my...
また父さんの書斎を散らかして
Scattering Daddy's studies again.
あらダメよ　そんな所に落書きしちゃ
Hey, no doodling on the floor.
落書きじゃないよ 見てて
I'm not doodling.
Watch!
それ　錬金術よね
That's... alchemy, isn't it?
父さんに習ったの
Did you learn that from Daddy?
いない人にどうやって習うのさ
How do we learn from someone who's not even here?
本読んだら書いてあったよ
It was in the books we read.
書いてあったって
Was in the books...
やっちゃいけないことだった
Were we not supposed to?
そんなことないわ
No, of course not!
You boys are amazing! As expected of Daddy's children.
すごい　さすが父さんの子ね
母さん　みんなに自慢しちゃおう
I'm going to have to brag to everyone about you two!
母さんが褒めてくれる
Mom praised us.
それがうれしくて　オレたちは錬金術にのめり込んだ
Because we liked that, we started getting into alchemy.
でも　その年の夏
But... in the summer of that year...
はやり病に見舞われて　母さんは逝ってしまった
Mom passed away due to an epidemic.
兄ちゃん　おなかすいた
Brother... I'm hungry.
寒いし　帰ろうよ
It's cold, too. Let's go home...
If Dad comes home-
お父さんが帰って来れば
あいつのことは言うな
Don't talk about him!
あんなヤツ父さんじゃない
He's not our Dad!
お母さんのお葬式にも帰って来なかったんだぞ
He didn't even come back for Mom's funeral.
お母さんを元に戻せないかな
I wonder if we could bring Mom back...
でも 人間をつくるのはやっちゃいけないことだって
But one of the books said that
transmutating humans isn't allowed.
本に書いてあったよ
だから　二人だけの秘密な
So... We'll keep it between us, all right?
You guys are here again.
またここに来てる
What do you want, Winry?
なんだよ　ウィンリィ
ばっちゃんが言ってたよ
Grandma said that if you cry for someone who's passed away, that person grieves as much as you cried for them.
死んだ人のことを思って泣くと
その涙の分だけ　あの世で死んだ人も悲しむって
泣いてなんかねぇよ
We're not crying!
お前こそ　お父さんとお母さんしょっちゅう出かけてるから
You're the one who cries all the time 'cause
your parents are always gone and you're lonely!
さみしくて泣いてるくせに
な　泣いてなんかないわよ
I-I never cry!
へへっ 本当かなぁ
Really?
あんたなんか心配して損した
I'm sorry I was ever worried about you now!
私より遅かったら飯抜きだからね
If you get home later than me, you don't get any supper!
なんだよそりゃ
What the heck is that? Wait up!
待てよ
ああっ 待ってよ
W-Wait for me!
いっただきます
Itadakimasu!
ほら　エドも牛乳飲んじまいな
Ed, you have to drink your milk, too.
牛乳嫌い
I hate milk.
飲まないとチビのまんまだよ
If you don't drink it, you'll be a runt forever.
誰がチビじゃ寸足らずババア
Who are you calling a runt, you midget hag!
なんだってこの豆粒チビ
What was that?! You pea-sized runt!
ミニマムババア
Minimum hag!
マイクロチビ
Micro runt!
アリンコサイズ
You're no bigger than an ant!
ミジンコサイズ
You're no bigger than a flea!
また学校で関係ない本を読んで
You were reading your book in school again...
授業ちゃんと聞かなきゃ
You have to pay attention in class, you know.
うるせぇなぁ
Oh, shut up.
ねえ　なんの本読んでるの
So, what book were you reading?
It's a secret.
秘密
ウィンリィには関係ねぇよ
None of your business, Winry.
ずるい　いつも二人で秘密にして
That's no fair! You two always keep little secrets!
じゃあねぇ
Later!
エド アル
Ed! Al! We're having stew tonight!
今日の晩ご飯　シチューだってさ
Awesome!
やった
おう　またあとでな
Okay. We'll see you later!
それにしてもシチューを発明した人は偉大だ
The person who invented stew is amazing.
牛乳が入ってるのにあんなにうまい
There's milk in it, yet it tastes so good.
なんだよそれ
What the heck?
The fact they thought of adding milk to vegetable soup is amazing.
野菜スープに牛乳を突っ込むっつう考えがすげぇよ
科学者にもそういう発想の転換が必要だな
It's important for scientists to drastically change their thinking sometimes.
そんなもんかなぁ
I wonder...
Yeah!
そうさ
人体錬成もきっと　そういう発想が必要なんだよ
Human transmutation probably needs something drastic like that, too!
それからオレたちは　母さんをよみがえらせるために
From then on, we researched human transmutation...
人体錬成について調べ
...and improved our abilities by training with
our alchemy master in order to revive our mother.
錬金術の師匠のもとで　腕を磨いた
何年も何年も掛かったけど
It took many years, but...
"I want to see Mom's smiling face again."
母さんの笑顔を見たい
母さんとまた楽しく暮らしたい
"I want to live happily with Mom again."
その思いで オレたちは
With those thoughts in our hearts, we...
出来た
There.
水　３５リットル
Water, 35L.
炭素　２０キログラム
Carbon, 20kg.
アンモニア　４リットル
Ammonia, 4L.
石灰　１.５キログラム
Lime, 1.5kg.
燐　８００グラム
Phosphorus, 800g.
塩分　２５０グラム
Salt, 250g.
硝石　１００グラム
Niter, 100g.
硫黄　８０グラム
Sulfur, 80g.
フッ素　７.５グラム
Fluorine, 7.5g.
鉄　５グラム
Iron, 5g.
珪素　３グラム
Silicon, 3g.
よし　構築式を書くぞ
All right, let's write the construction formula.
あとは　魂の情報だ
All that's left is the information about the soul.
いくぞ　アル
Let's do this, Al.
Right.
兄さん　なんか変だよ
Brother, something's wrong.
アル
Al!
まさか　リバウンド
Could this be... rebound?!
兄さん　兄さん
Brother!!!
Brother! Brother...
兄さん　兄さん
Brother!
兄さん
BROTHER!!!
アル
Al?
あれ　オレ何してたんだっけ
Huh? What was I doing?
よう
Yo.
誰
Who're you?
おお よくぞ聞いてくれました
Why, thanks for asking.
オレはお前たちが世界と呼ぶ存在
I'm an existence that you folks like to call the "world".
あるいは宇宙
In other words, the universe. In other words, God.
あるいは神
あるいは真理
In other words, the "Truth". In other words, entirety.
あるいは全
あるいは一
In other words, "one". And, I'm...
そしてオレは　お前だ
...you.
ようこそ　身の程知らずのバカ野郎
Welcome.
Mr. I'm-an-idiot-who-acts-all-high-and-mighty.
So noisy...
うるさいな
お前が欲しがってたものだろ
Isn't this what you wanted?
I'll show you the "truth".
見せてやるよ
真理を
ものすごい量の情報を　直接頭にぶち込まれたみたいだった
It was as though all of the information in the world was shoved directly into my head.
Stop it! My head's gonna burst!
やめろ　頭が割れる
分解される
I'm being disassembled...
イヤだ　やめてくれ
No! Stop it!
やめて
Stop!!!
頭が割れそうだった
I felt like my head was going to crack open.
だけど唐突に理解した
But I suddenly realized.
これが真理
This is the "Truth".
母さん
M... Mom...
どうだった
How was it?
そうだ
That's right...
オレの人体錬成理論は　間違っちゃいなかった
There were no errors in my human transmutation theory...
でも　足りないんだ
But I'm missing something!
もう少し先にオレの求めているものが
If I had gone a little further...
人体錬成の真理があった
I would've found what I was looking for; the truth to human transmutation!
お願いだ　もう一度見せてくれ
Please! Show it to me again!
ダメだね
No, no, no.
これだけの通行料だとここまでしか見せられない
I can only show you that much for that toll you've paid.
通行料
Toll?
そう　通行料
Yes, toll.
等価交換だろ 錬金術師
Equivalent exchange, is it not?
Mr. Alchemist.
くそっ　こんなことがあってたまるか
Dammit! Like I'd let this happen...
This... This wasn't...
こんな　こんなはずじゃ
ちくしょう　持っていかれたぁ
Dammit!!!
They took it away!!!
助けて　誰か
Help me... someone...
母さん　母さん
Mom... Mom...
No way... No...
ウソだ　違う
こんなの
This isn't...
こんなのを望んだんじゃない
This isn't what I wanted!!!
アル　アルフォンス
Al... Alphonse...
アルフォンス　アルフォンス
Alphonse! Alphonse!!!
オレのせいで
Because of me...
アルフォンス
Alphonse!!!
ちくしょう　ちくしょう
Dammit... Dammit!!!
返せよ　弟なんだ
Give him back... He's my little brother...
足だろうが腕だろうが
Whether it be an arm or a leg...
Or even my heart! You can take it!
心臓だろうがくれてやる
だから返せよ
So give him back...
He's my only brother!!!
たった一人の弟なんだよ
よう　まだセントラルにいたのか
Yo. You were still hangin' around in Central?
めでたく東方司令部に帰れることになった
They're letting me return to Eastern Headquarters.
Well, good work.
そりゃあご苦労さん
次に来るときゃ　准将ぐらいになっとけよ　大佐
You'd better at least be a Brigadier General the next time you come, all right, Colonel?
簡単に言う
You say that as if it's a walk in the park.
ああ そうだ
Oh yeah, if you're going back,
I'll go ahead and give this to you now.
帰るんなら先に渡しとこう
なんだ
What is it?
アイザック·マクドゥーガルに関する最終報告書だ
It's the final report about Isaac McDougal.
まだお前さんとこには　届いてないだろ
You haven't seen it yet, have you?
Yeah.
「シン国の錬丹術」
Eastern Alchemy from Xing?
そういうものがあるらしい
Apparently, something like that exists.
正直オレにはさっぱりだが　知ってるか
To be honest, I've got no idea, but...
Do you have a clue?
いや　初耳だ
No, never heard of it.
ところで　エルリック兄弟はどうしてる
By the way, how are the Elric brothers doing?
オレはあいつらの保護者じゃない
I'm not their keeper.
なあ　なんだってエドを国家錬金術師にしたんだ
Hey, why did you have Ed become a State Alchemist?
まだ子供なんだぜ
He's still a kid, you know?
軍にいる以上　いつか地獄を見るはめになる
As long as you're in the army,
you will experience Hell someday.
オレたちみたいにな
Just like we did.
地獄か
Hell, huh...
地獄なら見たさ　二人とも
If it's Hell, they've seen it already.
もう十分にな
Plenty of it, in fact...
4 Years Later
中佐　裏にもいませ
Lt. Colonel, they're not in the backyard ei-
これは
What is this...
Where are they?
どこだ　エルリック兄弟とやらは　どこにいる
Where are those Elric brothers?!
うるさいよ　デン
Pipe down, Den.
お客さんには
To customers, you have to...
ちょっとあんた　軍人がいきなりなんだい
Hey! What business does a soldier have here?
君たちの家に行ったぞ
I just came from your house!
なんだあの有様は
What in the world is all that?!
何を作った
What did you make?!
ごめんなさい　許してください
Sorry... Please forgive us.
ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい
We're sorry... We're sorry...
We're sorry...
君は
You're...
驚きました
I was shocked.
優れた錬金術師がいると聞いて訪ねてきたのですが
I heard there was a talented alchemist, so I came here.
まさか　こんな子供が
To think that a child performed human transmutation, though it was incomplete,
不完全とはいえ人体錬成を行い
魂の定着まで成し遂げるとは
and even managed to affix a soul.
He has more than enough to be a State Alchemist.
国家錬金術師になる資質が十分あります
国家錬金術師になると
If he became a State Alchemist, he'd have to fight as a soldier during times of emergencies.
有事の際は兵士として働くことになりますが
同時に　さまざまな特権や最高レベルの研究が可能となるのです
At the same time, the position comes with many privileges, and they'd be allowed to perform research of the highest level.
この子たちが元の体に戻る方法も　あるいは
They may be able to discover
a way to recover their bodies...
この子が血まみれで転がり込んで来た後にね
After these boys staggered in here
covered in blood, I went to their house.
私はこの子たちの家に行ったのさ
あれは　あれは人間なんかじゃなかった
That...
That was not human!
あんな恐ろしいものをつくるのが錬金術なのかい
Is alchemy what allowed them to create something horrible like that?!
私は反対だね
Then I'm against it!
また地獄を見ろってのかいこの子たちに
Are you telling these boys to look at Hell again?!
どうぞ
Please.
ありがと
Thank you.
あの　少尉さん
Umm... Lieutenant...
リザでいいわリザ·ホークアイ
Just call me Riza.
Riza Hawkeye. Nice to meet you.
よろしくね
リザさんは　人を撃ったことがあるの
Ms. Riza...
Have you ever shot somebody?
あるわ
I have.
軍人さんは嫌い
I don't like soldiers.
父さんも母さんも　戦場に連れていかれて殺されたから
Because Mom and Dad were taken to a battlefield and killed there.
そのうえ　エドとアルも連れていこうとしてる
And on top of that, you two are trying to take Ed and Al, too...
行くかどうかは　あの子たちが自分で決めることよ
Whether they come or not is up to them.
そう　自分で決めること
Yes... up to them.
強制はしない
I won't force you.
ただ私は可能性を提示する
I'm just presenting you with the possibilities.
進むのかとどまるのか
Whether they want to move forward or stay stuck in place.
Whether you want to end your life in despair or bow down to the army, seeking what possibilities lie there.
絶望のまま一生を終えるか
可能性を求めて軍に頭を垂れるか
It's those boys who have to make the decision.
それを決めるのは　あの子たち自身
If the possibility lies on that path, then you should move forward to return your body to normal.
そこに可能性があるならば
元の体に戻るために　前に進むべきだろう
たとえそれが　泥の河だったとしても
Even if that path is a muddy river.
リザさんはなぜ軍人になったの
Why did you become a soldier, Ms. Riza?
守るべき人がいるから
Because I have someone I want to protect.
帰るぞ
We're leaving.
はい
Yes, sir.
じゃあさよならね　お嬢さん
Well, this is good-bye, young lady.
ウィンリィです
My name is Winry.
そう　ウィンリィちゃん
I see. Winry.
また　会えるといいわね
I hope we'll meet again.
来るでしょうか
I wonder if he'll come?
来るさ
He will.
あの少年　無気力な目をしてましたけど
But his eyes looked spiritless...
そうかね
You think so?
あれは　火のついた目だ
Those... were burning eyes.
後悔しないかい
You won't regret it, will you?
うん　もう決めたことだから
Nope, I've already decided.
手術とリハビリでどれぐらい掛かる
How long would it take for both the surgery and rehab?
だいたい３年ってとこだね
I'd say about three years.
１年だ
One year.
血ヘドを吐くことになるよ
You're gonna be coughing up blood.
アル　もう少し我慢してくれな
Al, put up with it for a little longer, will ya?
オレが元の体に戻してやる
I'll put you back in your body.
うん　そのときは兄さんの体も一緒だよ
Yeah.
But when that time comes,
you're going to get your limbs back, too.
Yeah.
もう　体は完ぺきだね
Your body's all fixed up now, don't you think?
おう　あとは錬金術だ
Yeah! Just alchemy left to train now.
あれ以来使ってないからなぁ
Since I haven't used it since.
そっか　僕の魂を錬成したとき以来なんだ
Oh, so you haven't used it since you affixed my soul.
兄さん
Brother!
Perfect, perfect.
おお　ばっちりばっちり
すごいよ兄さん　錬成陣もなしに
That's amazing, Brother! You did it without a transmutation circle!
師匠と同じことができるようになったんだね
Just like how our master does it!
アルもできるだろ
You can do it, too, can't you?
できないよ兄さん
No, Brother.
あれを見なかったのか
You didn't see it?
あれって
See... what?
いや　なんでもない
No... never mind.
こら　私の機械鎧変形させたわね
Hey!!
You transformed my automail, didn't you?!
オレの頭は変形してもいいのかよ
So you're gonna transform my head instead?!
痛っ ったく
Ow... geez...
かわいげのねぇ機械オタだぜ
Uncute machine freak.
かわいげなくて結構　機械オタ結構
Like I care if I'm not cute!
I'm fine with being a machine freak, too!
私　あんたが元の体に戻るまで
I've decided to support you until you get your limbs back!
サポートするって決めたんだから
はあ
Wha?
試験を見学されるとはお珍しい
It's quite rare that you've decided to watch the exam, sir.
何
Well, I heard that a twelve year-old was being tested,
12歳の子供が来たというのでな
話の種に見ておこうと思ったのだよ
so I just thought I'd drop by so I would have something to talk about with my family.
おお　鋼の義手か
Ah, an arm made of steel...
東部の内乱で
I got it during the civil war in the west...
ああ イシュヴァールには手を焼いたな うん
Yeah, we sure had a lot of trouble with Ishbal.
誰
Who's that guy?
バカ　キング·ブラッドレイ大総統閣下だ
Idiot! That's Führer President King Bradley!
さあ　試験を始めたまえ
Now, let the examination begin.
錬成陣を描く道具は持っているか
Do you have something to draw a transmutation circle with?
いらないよそんなもん
I don't need something like that.
錬成陣もなしに
Without a transmutation circle...
これは　なかなか
Now this is quite something...
閣下
Your Excellency!
っていうふうに要人暗殺があるかもしれないからさ
...And some military figure may be assassinated like this, so...
この試験方法見直した方がいいんじゃない
You guys might want to think about changing this examination.
なかなか肝が据わっておる
Hmm, he's certainly got a lot of pluck.
だが世界の広さを知らぬ
But he doesn't understand the size of this world.
残りの試験も頑張りたまえ
Good luck with the rest of your exams, young alchemist.
若すぎる錬金術師よ
いつ抜いたんだよ
When did he draw his sword?
兄さん　試験大丈夫かなぁ
I wonder if Brother is doing all right on the exams...
ねえ　アル
Hey, Al.
うん　なあに
Hm? What's up?
エドが国家錬金術師になったら
If Ed becomes a State Alchemist...
この村出ていっちゃうの
...will you be leaving this town?
うん
Yeah.
これが国家資格の証し
This is the badge of a State Alchemist, the silver pocket watch.
銀時計
East City
Eastern Headquarters
拝命証と細かい規約はこれっと
Your certificate and the agreements are... here...
大総統も随分とまた皮肉な銘を
The Führer President has given you quite the ironic title...
何
What?
いや　おめでとう
No, congratulations.
これで君も　晴れて軍の狗だ
You're now a dog of the military.
大総統キング·ブラッドレイの名において
I, Führer President King Bradley, hereby appoint...
汝エドワード·エルリックを国家錬金術師に任命し
...thou, Edward Elric, as a State Alchemist,
銘 『鋼』を授ける
and bestow thee with the title, "Fullmetal".
鋼
Fullmetal?
That's right.
そう国家錬金術師に与えられる二つ名
The second name that's given to all State Alchemists.
君が背負うその名は
The name that you'll be carrying is...
鋼の錬金術師
"Fullmetal Alchemist".
いいねぇ　その重っ苦しい感じ
I like it. Sounds like something heavy to carry.
背負ってやろうじゃねぇの
But I'll do it.
兄さん　そろそろ着くよ
Brother, we're almost there.
Lior, huh...
リオールか
あの街に　アルの体を元に戻す手がかりが
There should be some clue there on how to get Al's body back...
賢者の石
The Philosopher's Stone...
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
ねえ　君は覚えていますか
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
約束　契り　初夏の風が包む
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
二人　寄り添った
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
無理な笑顔の裏
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
伸びた影をかくまう
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
だから　気づかぬふり　再生を選ぶ
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
テーブルの上の　震えない知らせ　待ち続けて
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
空白の夜も　来るはずのない朝も
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
全部わかってたんだ
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
ねえ　 いつか思い出すでしょう
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
果たせなかった　約束を抱いて
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
二人　歩き出す
Futari arukidasu
日本语字幕录入：FAYFAY
リオールの街を訪れたエドとアルは
Ed and Al, arriving in the city of Lior, meet Cornello, a man who preaches the revival of the dead.
死者の復活を標榜する男コーネロと出会う
漫游字幕组
http://popgo.net/bbs
祈り信じよ　されば救われん
Pray and believe, and thou shall be saved.
そう唱えるコーネロの指に
As Cornello preached those words, he wore the bright, red, Philosopher's Stone on his finger.
赤く光る　賢者の石があった
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第三話　邪教の街
Episode 3, City of Heresy.
真実から目を背けることで　得られる幸せとは
What, exactly, is the happiness that can be earned by turning away from reality?